gourmetads.com 2019-11-20

# Privacy Policy | Gourmet Ads

Skip to content

Privacy Policy[Benjamin Christie](https://www.gourmetads.com/articles/author/healthyads/ "Posts by Benjamin Christie")2019-09-09T14:24:20-04:00

Gourmet Ads Pty Ltd, an Australian company is bound by the Australian Privacy Act 1988 (as amended) and the Australian Privacy Principles (collectively, Privacy Law). This Privacy Policy describes the practices of how Gourmet Ads Pty Limited (“Gourmet Ads”, “Healthy Ads”, “House Ads”, “we” or “us”) collects, receives, uses and protects information in regards to Advertisers, Publishers and Visitors.

 **Privacy Commitment**

Gourmet Ads cares about an individual’s right to privacy and is committed to transparency and want you to be informed about what we do. We want you to fully understand how we may collect, use, and share data relating to individuals (like you), and the choices that are available to you.

 **What This Privacy Policy Covers**

This Privacy Policy covers two specific business operations and details the unique differences of each;

  1. Gourmet Ads Owned Websites
  2. The Gourmet Ads Advertising Service

###  **Definitions**

 **Cookies**

Cookies are a small text file (up to 4KB) that is stored in the user’s computer. Cookies provide a way for the website to recognize you and keep track of your preferences such as interests. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. The term ‘cookies’ is used as an umbrella term for various technologies used to identify browsers, such as HTML cookies, Flash cookies, scripts, web beacons and pixel tags. With each of these technologies, a small (text) file is placed by a web server on the device visiting the website or service, which can be read out during further use.

 **Non-Personally Identifiable Information (“Non-PII”)**

Non-Personally Identifiable Information, is simply data that is anonymous. For example, we consider the following to be Non-PII: your Post code or ZIP code, approximate location (e.g., DMA, Region, City, Country), your browser type, cookie IDs, Device type, browser type, plugin details, language preference, time zone, screen size, IP address, websites you may have visited, and advertisements viewed or clicked.

 **Personally Identifiable Information (“PII”)**

Personally Identifiable Information (PII) is information about you that can be used to contact you or identify you as an individual. PII may include: your name, phone number, email address, and physical address.

###  **Company Owned Websites**

Gourmet Ads owns a number of websites and by visiting any of the following Gourmet Ads owned websites, you acknowledge and agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy and to the processing of your Personal Information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

  * gourmetads.com / publishers.gourmetads.com
  * healthyads.com / publishers.healthyads.com
  * houseads.com / publishers.houseads.com

 **a) Collection of Information**

In order to use the Gourmet Ads Service as either an Advertiser or Publisher, we require personal (PII) information (or other information relevant as required) in regards to the purpose of commencing a commercial relationship with Gourmet Ads.  
The information we collect (when it is provided to us) is collected in the ways below:

  * You provide personal information through one of the Gourmet Ads websites;
  * You provide personal information over the phone.
  * You provide personal information via email.

We use the PII collected via this website for business purposes, such as marketing, recruiting and hiring, responding to general inquiries or customer support requests, and in the course of providing services to advertisers or publishers. We retain the PII collected via the website indefinitely, unless otherwise specified, or until we delete the PII pursuant to a request from the subject of the PII.

 **b) Security**

The security of your personal information is important to us. When you enter personal information via forms  on our website, we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL).

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. While we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

 **c) Third Party Services**

Third party services incorporated into our company websites, such as social media widgets or online advertising networks, may collect information about your visits to our site for purposes including interest-based advertising. This information could be combined with information collected from other sites. Such information may include, for example, pages visited, times and dates of visits, browser or operating system configuration, etc.

###  **The Gourmet Ads’ Advertising Program**

The Gourmet Ads’ Advertising Program allows advertisers to purchase ad space on publisher websites. Publishers want their ads to be relevant to their readers, which helps them to offer content for no cost or lower cost. Buyers want to use their advertising dollars efficiently by reaching the right audiences, and by measuring the effectiveness of their ads. To accomplish these goals, Advertisers and Publishers use the Gourmet Ads’ Advertising Program to engage in a variety of techniques, including interest-based advertising, real-time (or programmatic) advertising, contextual, and location-based advertising.

 **a) Opt Out**

The Gourmet Ads’ Advertising Program uses cookies to identify web browsers and to store data for advertising purposes, including interest-based advertising. There are many ways to opt-out of receiving targeted advertising. The primary ad server for the Gourmet Ads’ Advertising Program is Appnexus and you can opt out by visiting; <https://www.appnexus.com/platform-privacy-policy#choices>and Opting Out.

Industry trade associations maintain web pages where you can opt out of interest-based advertising by all participating companies:

  * Network Advertising Initiative: [http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices](https://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/)
  * Digital Advertising Alliance: [http://www.aboutads.info/choices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/)
  * Europe, [http://www.youronlinechoices.com](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/)
  * Digital Advertising Alliance of Canada <http://youradchoices.ca/choices/>

You can also choose to disable or selectively turn off cookies or third-party cookies in your web browser settings.

It is important to note that different devices (i.e. mobile, tablet and desktop) use different identifiers and different technologies, so that you must opt out separately from each web browser and each device that you would like to be opted out. If you opt-out of targeted advertising, we will no longer collect User Information described within this policy.

 **b) Non Personally Identifiable Information**

In regards to the Gourmet Ads Advertising Program specifically, we do not collect or use any Personally Identifiable Information (PII). Our ad serving platform is designed to use only non- Personally Identifiable Information (PII), and has contractual provisions that prohibit us from associating Platform cookies with PII.

 ** ** The Gourmet Ads’ Advertising Program may collect from visitors to Publisher Websites to deliver targeted advertisements the following; website addresses, date/time of visits, page view data, search keywords, visitor activities and actions on publisher’s sites, referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, geolocation (including city, country, zip code), click data, types of advertisements viewed; to enable advertisers to deliver targeted advertisements.

Gourmet Ads may also we collect for our legitimate business interests:

  * To operate and improve our technology;
  * To compile statistics and conduct research and development for our internal business purposes – all of which is done in aggregate anonymously without identifying visitors;
  * To enable standard advertising controls i.e frequency capping;
  * To prepare reports that summarize anonymous visitor activity;
  * To analyze and report on ad performance (such as tracking views of ad, as well as click-through rates on ads), campaign reporting, and campaign forecasting
  * To protect, investigate, and deter against fraudulent, unauthorized, or illegal activity.

 **c) Third Parties**  
Apart from our Primary Ad Server, Appnexus, we also work with a variety of Third Parties to deliver the Gourmet Ads Advertising Program to Publishers and Visitors of their websites. These Third-Party companies may separately collect, Non PII Information such as domain, referring website addresses, date/time of visits, page view data, search keywords, visitor activities and actions on publisher’s sites, referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, geolocation (including city, country, zip code), click data, types of advertisements viewed; to enable advertisers to deliver targeted advertisements. Third Party companies may include but are not limited to Advertisers and their agencies or media buying companies, Amazon, Captify, Criteo, Eyeota, Index Exchange, Google, Media.net, Magnetic, Nielsen, Oracle, Quantcast, Rubicon Project and Salesforce.

 **d) Security**

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, ** ** we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

 **Legal**

We reserve the right to disclose your personal information as required or permitted by law.

 **Changes to this Privacy Policy**

Gourmet Ads reserves the right to change this privacy policy from time to time in order to reflect, for example, changes to our practices or for other operational, legal or regulatory reasons.

 **Further Information about our Privacy Policy**

If you have any questions, concerns, or suggestions regarding our Privacy Policy or how we process your data, please email Gourmet Ads or in writing to;

Gourmet Ads Pty Limited  
PO Box 1736  
Warriewood, NSW, 2102  
Australia

 _This Privacy Policy was last updated on the 6th  May 2018_

### Let the Gourmet Ads team walk you through all the options available to ensure that your Food, Supermarket, Beverage or Kitchen campaign has the best possible combination of Premium Guaranteed Inventory, First Party Data and Programmatic elements.
